<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MARIA PAULA MALDONADO MENDOZA on MPMM</title>
    <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MARIA PAULA MALDONADO MENDOZA on MPMM</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Being Ruderal</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/18-onbeingruderal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/18-onbeingruderal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lecture performance on spontaneity, adaptation, bad herbs, and unwelcome thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Text [below] by Maria Paula Maldonado. • Visuals, animation and sound by Thomas Mayer. • Special thanks to Constanza Carvajal with whom we created the installation environment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;25th of March, 2023. Part of the program &lt;em&gt;Ruderal Practices&lt;/em&gt; organized by Make-up e.V. Generously funded by Stiftung Kunstfonds - NEUSTART KULTUR, and the Beauftragten der Bundesregierung für Kultur und Medien (BKM).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wer ist diese Frau? (Who is this woman?)</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/17-whoisthiswoman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/17-whoisthiswoman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For International Women’s Day and Women’s History Month 2023, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bdkw.org/&#34;&gt;Library of FLINTA* Artists, Weimar&lt;/a&gt; in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.11m3.de/&#34;&gt;Projektraum 11m3&lt;/a&gt;, presented &lt;a href=&#34;https://bdkw.org/wer-ist-diese-frau/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who is this Woman?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; a window exhibition exploring the representation of FLINTA* people in the arts through the lens of an iconic photograph of an unknown woman taken by Erich Consemüller in 1927. The names associated with the Bauhaus objects she is presenting are credited: Club Chair B3 by Marcel Breuer, mask by Oskar Schlemmer, dress fabric by Lis Beyer. But not hers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruderal Dinner</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/15-ruderaldinner/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/15-ruderaldinner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A big table, unmatching cutlery, nettle pesto, foraged mushrooms (eatable and not), uneven chairs, a white tablecloth, and baked polenta. Another table, a typewriter, a bonfire, fingers typing words translated from thoughts (some undesired), paper, a microphone, a loudspeaker, sentences repeated out loud in loops, lights, and chairs. A dinner and an experimental ritual to deal better together with unwanted plants, unwanted thoughts, and unwanted feelings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/15-ruderaldinner/img/15-RuderalDinner1_hu14924426506705050905.jpg&#34;&#xA;    /&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo: Maria Paula Maldonado&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elements of Coexistence</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/16-elementsofcoexistence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/16-elementsofcoexistence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Facing climate change, environmental destruction, and extinctions as well as individualistic mindsets, inequalities, binary thinking and Eco-anxiety, the project Elements of Coexistence aims to reflect poetically on our shared existence on planet Earth through our shared global commons, such as water, soil, seeds, air, and sunlight.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The project addresses environmental issues by questioning how to dwell in our fragile historical moment while sharing diverse perspectives and points of view.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first stage of &amp;ldquo;Elements of Coexistence&amp;rdquo;, a project in collaboration with Elham Asadpour, took the shape of an exhibition with the same title at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.make-up.space/&#34;&gt;Make-up&lt;/a&gt;, in Berlin, Germany, from the 29th of September until the 3rd of October 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruderal Practices</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/14-ruderalpractices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/14-ruderalpractices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In response to the theme and provocations for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://2022.projectspacefestival-berlin.com/&#34;&gt;2022 Project Space Festival&lt;/a&gt;, the project &amp;ldquo;Ruderal Practices&amp;rdquo; intended to consider and reflect on our individual, collective and artistic practices through the lens of the Ruderal, inspired by the spontaneous urban ecologies of Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ruderal Practices&amp;rdquo; explores how we can inhabit, survive and grow in in-between and precarious environments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;curatorial-text&#34;&gt;Curatorial Text&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We take the concept &amp;ldquo;ruderal&amp;rdquo;° in order to reflect on our individual, spatial and collective practices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above.&#xA;See form.html in the layouts folder **&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kurzgesagt, in vollem Umfang (In a nutshell, to the fullest extent)</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/12-kurzgesagt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/12-kurzgesagt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anybody anywhere who has a device with internet acces -such as a computer, a tablet or a smartphone- can watch in real time what is happening around Goethe and Schiller&amp;rsquo;s statue in Theaterplatz, Weimar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many Webcams installed in the public space in various cities across Germany. Some of these cameras allow people to access the &amp;ldquo;views&amp;rdquo; that are being captured, but many other cameras do not.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project questions our permanently surveilled lives, the continuos gathering of data from everyday life, and the power relation between those who observe and those who do not know are the ones being observed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigation durch Umrisse (Navigation through contours)</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/11-navigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/11-navigation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Navigating through contours is a project that reflects on how to navigate through the known and the unknown, through that which is near and that which is far. With the help of marks, maps, frames and grids, that create the contours of our own paths and limits of positioning, repositioning, steering and keep going. The project ponders on the representation of places, objects, situations and concepts that we grasp to in order to try to understand them and be able to relate to them. It also speculates on the struggles that living beings are facing in order to adapt and survive to new environments, and the transformations that non-living beings are undergoing; as is the case of glaciers that are retreating and plants that are growing on higher and higher terrains in order not to disappear. Both glaciers and plants, as beings that inhabit the world within the framework of their own contours, which in some cases are also threatened.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bibliothek der Künstler*innen, Weimar (Library of FLINTA* Artists, Weimar)</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/13-bdkw/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/13-bdkw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://bdkw.org/&#34;&gt;Library of FLINTA* Artists, Weimar&lt;/a&gt;, is an artistic project that exists as a growing archive alongside a public outreach programme around a collection. This collection includes donated and found secondary material such as artworks, documents and images that form a usable resource to contribute to the mediation of the city’s resident FLINTA*-artists, past and present. Due to its ever-changing nature, the library can exist in many forms and spaces, both digital and physical. The aim is to act as a meeting place to collaborate, research and share with others about the collection. This will initiate events such as workshops, exhibitions and performances.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BUNKERS: Architecture of fear, architecture of hope</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/10-bunkers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/10-bunkers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;BUNKERS: Architecture of fear, architecture of hope&amp;rdquo; is an artistic research project that reflects on the topic of bunkers -as the ultimate shelters-.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A bunker is an architecture of fear and an architecture of hope. It is a construction -material and conceptual- that offers shelter from various and specific threats. The figure of the bunker, and the categories of fear and hope that are embedded in bunkers, are powerful tools for thinking about living on a damaged planet facing upcoming social and environmental catastrophes, reviewing our collective past, facing our present, and looking towards a possible better future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bird Choir - Mimicking Is Surviving</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/9-birdchoir/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/9-birdchoir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In order to defend a territory, to attract a mate, and to survive, birds have developed the ability to mimick and to integrate various and alien sounds to their repertoire of songs.&#xA;The Bird Choir reflects on how we, humans, like birds, incorporate in our lives other strange sounds to survive, to fit, to be anonymous, to be safe, to protect us and to protect our relatives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/9-birdchoir/img/9-BirdChoir1-FKB_hu6544723752238309622.jpg&#34;&#xA;    /&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;            &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo: Konrad Behr&lt;/em&gt; • Walk of Art. Bauhaus Universität Weimar, Weimar, Germany.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I come from…</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/8-icomefrom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/8-icomefrom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the question &amp;ldquo;Where do you come from?&amp;rdquo; is asked, the first answer is usually related to a country of origin or a nationality. But what can the name of a sovereign state say about a person? Is it possible to get a glimpse of an individual from a country’s name that is attached to the myth of national identity? Is a flag that represents a specific region defined by political borders enough to reflect the complexity and multiplicity of origins that shape a human being?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Moon</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/7-themoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/7-themoon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The installation is an invitation to contemplate, to lay down, to think, to meditate, to feel, to sleep, to wait, to remember, to rest, to hope, to wonder. Conceived as an antidote to the exponential acceleration and hyperconnectivity that come with the distractions and anxieties of the present moment THE MOON refers to the possibility of downtime from the everyday. In perpetual interplay with its counterpart the sun, nighttime can be a break that brings about a sense of wonder and awe. The artists consider the spatial and temporal disorientation of nighttime as a possibility to explore notions of the profound, the mysterious and the unknown.&lt;/em&gt; ~ Xenia Schürmann&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 class=&#34;f2 f2-ns measure-narrow lh-solid&#34;&gt;&#xA;  MARIA PAULA MALDONADO MENDOZA&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p class=&#34;f4 measure lh-copy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  (she/her)&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;f3&#34;&gt;BIO&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&#34;f5 measure lh-copy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  b. 1988 Bogotá, Colombia.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p class=&#34;f5 measure lh-copy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Artist, researcher and cultural manager currently living and working in Berlin, Germany. She holds a B.A. in Arts from Los Andes University in Bogotá, Colombia, and an M.F.A. in Public Art and New Artistic Strategies from Bauhaus-Universität Weimar, Germany, led by Prof. Danica Dakić. &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&#34;f5 measure lh-copy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Through her projects, she approaches topics such as the possible upcoming environmental and social catastrophes, environment and ecology, hope, data and surveillance, and the construction of identities. Her work combines various new and traditional media including site-specific interventions and installations, publications, collage, texts, printmaking, painting, actions in public space and archiving, among others. She has exhibited her work in individual and group exhibitions in Germany, Colombia and Online.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data protection</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are very delighted that you have shown interest in our enterprise. Data protection is of a particularly high priority for the management of the Maria Paula Maldonado. The use of the Internet pages of the Maria Paula Maldonado is possible without any indication of personal data; however, if a data subject wants to use special enterprise services via our website, processing of personal data could become necessary. If the processing of personal data is necessary and there is no statutory basis for such processing, we generally obtain consent from the data subject.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imprint</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/imprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 14:47:22 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/imprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;imprint&#34;&gt;Imprint&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maria Paula Maldonado&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Papierstraße 11&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;13409 Berlin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Germany&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:mpm.mariapaula@gmail.com&#34;&gt;mpm.mariapaula@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All rights reserved. No unauthorized use, copying or reproduction of the images and/or text, whether for personal or commercial purposes, without the written permission of the artist (see details above).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The artist does not take responsibility for the views expressed in, or contents of, external links.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;© 2023 Maria Paula Maldonado&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Typography Styles &amp; Element Examples</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/elements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;flex-l&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;div class=&#34;w-50-l pr4-l&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h6 class=&#34;ttu tracked black-30 pv3 mt5 bt b--black-10&#34;&gt;Font Sizes&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100 overflow-x-auto&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;table class=&#34;w-100 mb2&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;          &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&#34;tc f-headline b b--black-10 bg-white-60 v-base&#34;&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&#34;tc f-subheadline b b--black-10 bg-white-60 v-base&#34;&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&#34;tc f1 b b--black-10 bg-white-60 v-base&#34;&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&#34;tc f2 b b--black-10 bg-white-60 v-base&#34;&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&#34;tc f3 b b--black-10 bg-white-60 v-base&#34;&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&#34;tc f4 b b--black-10 bg-white-60 v-base&#34;&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&#34;tc f5 b b--black-10 bg-white-60 v-base&#34;&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&#34;tc f6 b b--black-10 bg-white-60 v-base&#34;&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&#34;tc black-50 f6 fw2 pa1&#34;&gt;6rem&lt;br&gt;(96px)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&#34;tc black-50 f6 fw2 pa1&#34;&gt;5rem&lt;br&gt;(80px)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&#34;tc black-50 f6 fw2 pa1&#34;&gt;3rem&lt;br&gt;(48px)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&#34;tc black-50 f6 fw2 pa1&#34;&gt;2.25rem&lt;br&gt;(36px)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&#34;tc black-50 f6 fw2 pa1&#34;&gt;1.5rem&lt;br&gt;(24px)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&#34;tc black-50 f6 fw2 pa1&#34;&gt;1.25rem&lt;br&gt;(20px)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&#34;tc black-50 f6 fw2 pa1&#34;&gt;1rem&lt;br&gt;(16px)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&#34;tc black-50 f6 fw2 pa1&#34;&gt;.875rem&lt;br&gt;(14px)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/table&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h6 class=&#34;ttu tracked black-30 pv3 mt5 bt b--black-10&#34;&gt;Type Samples&lt;/h6&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h1 class=&#34;f-headline measure-narrow lh-solid&#34;&gt;Head&amp;shy;line&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h1 class=&#34;f-subheadline measure-narrow lh-solid&#34;&gt;Sub&amp;shy;head&amp;shy;line&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;    &lt;h1 class=&#34;f2 f1-ns measure-narrow lh-title&#34;&gt;Level 1 Heading&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p class=&#34;f4-ns measure lh-copy&#34;&gt;One page to rule them all...well, not really. This page displays sample typography and page elements to illustrate their style. Things like headings and paragraphs showing the beautiful type scale, form elements, tabular data, and image layouts just to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No todo brilla (Not everything shines)</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/6-notodobrilla/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/6-notodobrilla/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The desperation produced by the impatience of waiting for something to happen, to pass. For the traffic jam to pass, for the taxi to pass, for the rain to pass, for the insecurity to pass, for the hostility to pass. Sometimes there are distractions: a dog, one graffiti, a familiar song, or someone falling. The thought changes and comes back to oneself: what if it is me who falls? Anxiety and uneasiness return. The traffic jam continues, the taxi doesn&amp;rsquo;t pass, it&amp;rsquo;s still raining, it&amp;rsquo;s still unsafe, and it&amp;rsquo;s still hostile.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plumarias (Featherworks)</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/5-plumarias/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/5-plumarias/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Feathers were used by many of the indigenous communities in the Americas. They were generally used as body ornaments, garments, capes, headdresses, or were glued to the body to generate body designs. Sometimes they were used to decorate the bodies of the dead, burial bundles or, sometimes, when only the bones remained, they were decorated with feathers and used in ceremonies. Feathers were also used to decorate objects, staffs, masks and statues. Feathers could be obtained hundreds or thousands of kilometres away from where the feathers were made, and were brought there by exchange between many communities. The effort made to obtain feathers speaks to the importance of feathers in these communities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estéticas histriónicas (Histrionic Aesthetics)</title>
      <link>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/4-esteticashistrionicas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mariapaulamaldonado.github.io/blog/4-esteticashistrionicas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;One of the main uses we have given to paint has been to beautify: we paint the walls of the places we live in and hang painted pictures on them to make them more welcoming, we paint our cars to make them more eye-catching and we even paint objects to innocently hide their nature and raise their status.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Similarly, in beauty salons, procedures involving painting are very common: there are changes of color and shape in the hair, application of pigments on the face to cover imperfections, on the lips and eyes to highlight their expressions and finally the application of layers of nail polish to transform those hard skin surfaces into elements with the potential to communicate moods and personalities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
